BASSEL ASSI

FRONT-END DEVELOPER



PERSONAL DETAILS

Reggio Emillia

bassel-assi@live.com, +39 320 1538330 Website: master--basselassi.netlify.app LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/basselassi

Github: github.com/baselasi

PROFILE

I am an Industrial Engineer pursuing a Master's degree in Process and Material Engineering at Trieste University. My journey into programming began with self-learning, mastering HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. As I dug into front-end development, getting the hang of React and Bootstrap was a key part, making me better at creating dynamic and responsive web applications.

Enrolling in a Reindal programming course expanded my knowledge, culminating in an internship. Where i am currently working towards becoming a full-stack developer, I am gaining practical experience in a real-world software environment. I am an intelligent, disciplined, and responsible individual with a strong motivation for learning and a natural curiosity that drives my continuous pursuit of knowledge.

EMPLOYMENT

FRONT-END DEVELOPER/intershipe

Nov 2023 - Present

REINDAL, Reggio nell'Emilia

- Proficiently worked with SVELTE framework to enhance and create new components.
- Created API calls to both local servers and Microsoft Azure servers
- Collaborated closely with the backend team to identify and communicate issues, fostering a collaborative development environment.
- Worked on improving app responsiveness, ensuring a seamless user experience across different screen sizes.
- Actively participated in team meetings to discuss and solve complex problems related to project development.
- Collaborated with team members to identify innovative solutions, contributing to a more effective problem-solving process.
- Utilized POSTMAN for API testing, creating organized collections for efficient testing processes.

Pizza Delivery Jan 2022 - Sep 2023

PIZZA PARINI, Trieste

Waiter Jul 2021 - Jan 2022

HOSTARIA MALCANTON, TRIESTE

Car Salesman Jan 2021 - Jul 2021

REAUTO, Martinengo-Bergamo

EDUCATION

Web developer course Oct 2023 - Nov 2023

Reindal, Reggio nell'Emilia

I completed a 200-hour front-end development course using SVELTE, offered by REINDAL, a software development company based in Reggio nell'Emilia.

Master degree in Process And Material Engineering

Università degli studi di Trieste, TRIESTE, Trieste, Trieste

Sep 2017 - Present

Bachelor Degree In Industrial Engineering

Università degli studi di Trieste, TRIESTE, Trieste, Trieste

Sep 2012 - Jun 2016

	Sk	$\langle 1 \rangle$	L	LS
--	----	---------------------	---	----

JAVASCRIPT/TYPESCRIPT	REACT	
SVELTE	NODE/EXPRESS.JS	
DART/FLUTTER	BOOTSTRAP	
TAILWIND	MONGODB	
QUALITIES		
■ Problem Solving	■ Flexibility	
■ Team Work	■ Stress Resistance	
LANGUAGES		
Italian	English	
Arabic		

DEVELOPMENT TOOLS

VSC VITE

GIT/GITHUB CANVA

POSTMAN FLOWBITE

Azure NPM